Zac Delventhal

jobs@zacis.me - 651-447-0519 - linkedin.com/in/delventhalz - zacis.me

Full stack engineer with nine years of experience in web development and additional contributions to open source, mobile, games, and blockchain. Proven success as an individual contributor, tech lead, ambassador, and instructor.

Skills

- Languages: TypeScript, JavaScript, Python, Rust, Clojure
- Tools: Git, Bash, Cypress, Jest, Docker, OpenAPI
- Frontend: React, React Native, Svelte, Angular, Om
- Backend: Node, Express, SQL, GraphQL, Flask

- Infrastructure: AWS, GCP, Docker, Sovrin, Hyperledger - Soft Skills: Peer mentoring, teaching, documentation

Experience

Federal Reserve Bank of Minneapolis | Senior Software Engineer

May 2022 – Present

Tech: TypeScript, React, Node, AWS, Cypress, Jest

Minneapolis, MN

- Drove adoption of high precision numbers beyond JavaScript's default 15 significant figures

- Led type overhaul, speeding development by encoding complex domain logic directly in type definitions

Prime Digital Academy | Part-time Instructor

Mar 2023 – Oct 2023

Tech: JavaScript, React, Node, Jest, SQL

- Introduced the use of automated tests to guide students and speed grading

Cargill | Senior Software Engineer

Oct 2021 – May 2022

Tech: JavaScript, Svelte, GraphQL, Apollo, Node, AWS

Minneapolis, MN

Minneapolis, MN

- Addressed long-standing load issues, improving Largest Contentful Paint by 10x with custom pre-fetch routine

Galvanize | Lead Enterprise Instructor

Dec 2020 - Aug 2021

Tech: JavaScript, Solidity, Sawtooth, Node, Mocha, Chai, Docker

Remote

Unveil. Social | Lead Developer

Apr 2019 – Nov 2020

Tech: JavaScript, React Native, Redux, Redux Saga, GCP, Sovrin

Minneapolis, MN

- Led international team in development of unique peer-to-peer mobile dating app

Best Buy | Full Stack Developer IV

May 2019 - Oct 2019

Tech: TypeScript, React Native Web, Node, Groovy, Redux, RxJava, Jest

Richfield, MN

- Coordinated dozens of APIs across Best Buy's heterogenous ecosystem in languages like Node, Groovy, and Swift

Thrivent | Application Engineer

Aug 2018 - May 2019

Tech: TypeScript, Angular, Node, AWS, RxJS

Minneapolis, MN

- Led adoption of RESTful standards for new "Term IV" API, improving usability and predictability

ReBootKamp | Lead Instructor

Aug 2018

Tech: Hyperledger Sawtooth, Ethereum

Amman, Jordan

Bitwise IO | Senior Software Engineer

Jun 2016 – Aug 2018

Tech: JavaScript, Python, Rust, Clojure, Node, MongoDB, Docker

Minneapolis, MN

- Core maintainer and ambassador for Hyperledger, focusing on REST API design and developer education

Projects

Taelmoor | Designer, Mobile Developer

taelmoor.com

Tech: TypeScript, React Native, Expo, Express, SQL

Hyperledger Grid | Architect, Lead Engineer

github.com/hyperledger/grid

Tech: Python, Rust, JavaScript

Education

Hack Reactor | Advanced Software Engineering Immersive

Feb 2016

Central Connecticut State University | BFA in Acting

Mar 2008